<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wlpotter/syriaca-wright-catalog/master/schemas/enrich-syriaca.rnc" type="compact"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/srophe/wright-catalogue/master/parameters/wright-mss.css"?>
<TEI xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Content pending</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <editionStmt>
        <p>Content pending</p>
      </editionStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <p>Content pending</p>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <msDesc>
          <msIdentifier>
            <idno type="URI">414</idno>
            <altIdentifier>
              <idno type="BL-Shelfmark">Add. 14,648</idno>
            </altIdentifier>
          </msIdentifier>
          <msContents>
            <summary/>
            <textLang mainLang="syr"/>
            <msItem defective="true">
              <locus to="" from="1b"/>
              <author ref="">Hieronymus</author>
              <title ref="" xml:lang="en">Histories of the Egyptian Solitaries</title>
              <rubric xml:lang="syr">ܦܢܩܝܬܐ ܕܬܫ̈ܥܝܬܐ ܕܝܚ̈ܝܕܝܐ ܡܨܪ̈ܝܐ</rubric>
              <incipit xml:lang="syr"/>
              <quote xml:lang="syr">
                <locus from="" to=""/>
              </quote>
              <note>compiled by Hieronymus, ܐܝܪܘܢܡܝܣ. <bibl>See Add. 12,173, no. 1</bibl></note>
              <note>The work is divided into two parts, the first of which, fol. 1 b, is imperfect
                at the end, and the second, fol. 47 a, at the beginning. This defect is very
                ancient, for at the foot of fol. 46 b there is the following note, of not later date
                than the xiith cent. : ܡܢ ܗܪܟܐ ܐܙܝܠܝܢ ܟܘܪ̈ܣܐ ܚܡܫܐ܀ ܘܣܒܪ ܐܢܐ ܕܗܠܝܢ ܬܫܥ̈ܝܬܐ ܪ̈ܘܪܒܬܐ.
                ܕܦܘܠܐ ܪܒܐ ܘܩܕܡܝܐ. ܘܕܗܠܝܢ ܕܒܬܐܒܐܝܣ܀</note>
            </msItem>
            <msItem>
              <locus to="" from="125a"/>
              <author ref=""/>
              <title ref="" xml:lang="en">A life of <persName>Gregory Thaumaturgus</persName>,
                bishop of Neo-Caesarea </title>
              <rubric xml:lang="syr">ܬܫܥܝܬܐ ܥܠ ܢܨܚ̈ܢܘܗܝ ܕܛܘܒܢܐ ܓܪܝܓܪܝܘܣ ܐܦܣܩܦܐ ܕܢܐܩܣܪܝܐ.. </rubric>
              <incipit xml:lang="syr">ܐܚ̈ܝ ܢܬܠ ܬܫܒܘܚܬܐ ܠܐܠܗܐ̣. ܗ̇ܘ ܕܨ̇ܒܐ ܒܚ̈ܝܐ ܕܟܠܗܘܢ ܒܢ̈ܝ ܐܢܫܐ.
                ܕܢܐܬܘܢ ܠܝܕܥܬܐ ܕܫܪܪܐ ܘܢܚ̣ܘܢ. ܘܢܬܥܠܘܢ ܒܕܘܒܪ̈ܝܗܘܢ ܪܘܚܢܐܝܬ. ܠܪܘܡܐ ܓܐܝܐ ܕܫܡܝܐ. ܕܟܕ
                ܒܣܪܢܐܝܬ ܡܬܚܙܝܢ ܕܡܗܠܟܝܢ ܥܠ ܐܪܥܐ̣ ܒܛܘܦܣܐ ܕܡܠܐ̈ܟܐ ܡܕܝܪܝܢ ܩܕܡ ܪܒܘܬܗ ܕܐܠܗܐ. ܠܐ ܗܘܐ ܓܝܪ ܥܠ
                ܛܘܪ̈ܐ ܘܒܡܥܪ̈ܐ ܘܒܫܩ̈ܝܦܐ. ܘܒܦܥܪ̈ܝܗ̇ ܕܐܪܥܐ. ܣܟܝܘ ܐܢܫܐ ܠܦܘܪܩܢܗ ܕܐܠܗܐ ܒܠܚܘܕ ܐܠܐ ܐܦ ܒܓܘ
                ܫܝܢܐ ܕܥܕܬܐ ܐܫܬܟܚܘ ܓܢܒܪ̈ܝ ܚܝܠܐ̇. ܟܕ ܠܒܝܫܝܢ ܙܝܢܐ ܕܪܘܚܐ ܘܙܟܝܢ ܠܬܟܬܘܫܐ ܕܒܥܠܕܒܒܐ. ܒܚܝܠܗ
                ܕܙܩܝܦܐ ܐܝܟ ܕܥܠ ܛܘܒܢܐ ܓܪܝܓܪܝܘܣ. ܐܦܣܩܘܦܐ ܕܢܐܩܣܪܝܐ ܨܒܝܢܢ ܕܢܫܬܥܐ. ܗܢܐ ܕܝܢ ܡܢ ܩܕܝܡ ܐܝܬܗܘܝ
                ܗܘܐ ܡܕܒܪܝܐ ܘܡܬܦܪܦܥ ܒܚܘܪܒܐ ܕܛܘܪ̈ܐ ܕܢܫܟܚ ܬܡܢ ܠܫܝܢܗ̇ ܕܒܪܝܬܐ̣. ܏ܘܫ.</incipit>
              <quote xml:lang="syr">
                <locus from="" to=""/>
              </quote>
              <explicit xml:lang="syr">
                <locus to="" from=""/>
              </explicit>
              <finalRubric xml:lang="syr">
                <locus to="" from=""/>
              </finalRubric>
              <note/>
            </msItem>
          </msContents>
          <physDesc>
            <objectDesc form="codex">
              <supportDesc material="perg">
                <extent>
                  <measure unit="content_pending" quantity="-1"/>
                </extent>
                <foliation/>
                <collation/>
                <condition>
                  <list>
                    <item>
                      <p>Vellum, about 10 1/8 in. by 6 3/4, consisting of 136 leaves. The quires,
                        signed with letters, were originally 23 in number, but five of them, ܝܐ ـــ
                        ܙ, are lost. Each page is divided into two columns, of from 28 to 36 lines.
                        This volume is written in a fine, regular Estrangela of the vith cent., </p>
                    </item>
                  </list>
                </condition>
              </supportDesc>
              <layoutDesc>
                <p>Content pending</p>
              </layoutDesc>
            </objectDesc>
            <handDesc>
              <handNote scope="" script=""
                medium="">
                <desc></desc>
              </handNote>
            </handDesc>
            <additions>
              <p></p>
              <list>
                <item>
                  <locus from="1a" to=""/>
                  <p>The original writing on fol. 1 a has been in great part effaced. Some lines at
                    the foot of the page show that the manuscript was once the property of a convent
                    (ܠܕܝܪܐ ܕܐܡܝܪܐ). A more recent note states that it belonged by purchase to the
                    brothers Matthew, Abraham, Joseph and Theodore, of Tagrit</p>
                  <p><quote xml:lang="syr">ܐܝܬܘܗܝ ܟܬܒܐ ܗܢܐ ܕܡܬܝ ܘܐܒܪܗܡ ܘܝܘܣܦ ܘܬܐܕܘܪܣ ܐܚ̈ܐ ܒܓܢܣܐ ܕܝܢ ܬܓܪ̈ܝܬܢܝܐ. ܕܩ̈ܢܘܗܝ ܡܢ
                      ܙܝܢܬܐ ܕܐܠܗܐ. ܘܕܘܥܬܐ ܕܐܦܝ̈ܗܘܢ. ܟܠ ܕܝܢ ܕܫ̇ܐܠ ܠܗ ܕܢܩܪܐ ܒܗ. ܏ܘܫ.</quote></p>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <locus from="135b" to=""/>
                  <p>The original note on fol. 135 b has also been erased, and in its place is
                    substituted one, which records the presentation of the volume, with others, to
                    the convent of S. Mary Deipara by the above-mentioned Tagritans.</p>
                  <p>
                    <quote xml:lang="syr">ܐܝܬܘܗܝ ܟܬܒܐ ܗܢܐ ܕܕܝܪܐ ܩܕܝܫܬܐ ܕܒܝܬ ܝܠܕܬ ܐܠܗܐ ܕܣܘܪ̈ܝܝܐ
                      ܕܒܡܕܒܪܐ ܕܐܣܩ̈ܝܛܐ. ܣܡܘܗܝ ܕܝܢ ܠܟܬܒܐ ܗܢܐ ܒܗ̇ ܒܕܝܪܐ. ܡܬܝ ܘܐܒܪܗܡ ܘܝܘܣܦ ܘܬܐܕܘܪܣ ܐܚ̈ܐ
                      ܬܓܪ̈ܝܬܢܝܐ. ܗ̇ܢܘܢ ܕܗ̣ܢܘܢ ܒܢ̣ܘ ܘܐܬܩ̣ܢܘ ܠܕܘܟܬܐ ܩܕܝܫܬܐ ܕܐܡܝܪܐ. ܟܠ ܕܝܢ ܕܠܚܐ
                      ܥܘܗܕܢܗܘܢ ܡܢ ܗܢܐ ܟܬܒܐ ܐܘ ܡܢ ܚܕ ܡܢ ܗܠܝܢ ܟܬܒ̈ܐ ܕܝܠܗܘܢ. ܢܗܘܐ ܚܪܡ ܡܢ ܐܒܐ ܘܡܢ ܒܪܐ.
                      ܘܡܢ ܪܘܚܐ ܚܝܐ ܘܩܕܝܫܐ. ܐܝܢ ܘܐܡܝܢ܀.</quote>
                  </p>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <locus from="136b" to=""/>
                  <p>Fol. 136 was once covered on both sides with writing, which has been almost
                    wholly effaced. The recto now contains nothing but a few ornamental devices. On
                    the verso there is a note of comparatively modern date, stating that a person,
                    whose name has been rubbed out, read this book. He says that he was a native of
                    Ras-'ain, from the convent of Mar Athanasius; that his father's name was
                      <persName>Severus bar Habib</persName>, and that his spiritual father was
                    Anastasius, the librarian كُتُبيّ), of the said convent</p>
                  <p>
                    <quote xml:lang="syr">ܐܬܛܝܒ ܘܩܪܐ ܒܟܬܒܐ ܗܢܐ . . . ܡܢ ܥܘܡܪܐ ܩܕܝܫܐ ܕܡܪܝ ܐܬܢܘܣ ܘܐܬܪܐ
                      ܕܝܠܗ ܪܝܫܥܝܢܐ ܡܕܝܢܬܐ ܐܒܐ ܪܘܚܢܝܐ ܕܝܠܗ ܐܢܣܛܣ ܟܬܒܝܐ ܕܝܠܗ ܕܥܘܡܪܐ ܘܦܓܪܢܝܐ ܣܘܪ ܒܪ
                      ܚܒܝܒ ܫܟܦܐ ܐܚ̈ܝ ܡܛܠ ܡܪܢ ܚܣܘ ܠܢ ܟܢܝܫܐܝܬ ܡܛܠ ܡܪܢ ܐܠܗܐ ܢܚܣܐ ܠܗܘܢ ܐܡܝܢ.</quote>
                  </p>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <locus from="136b" to=""/>
                  <p>Below there is written, in a different hand, the name Stephen, ܐܣܛܦܢܐ (sic)</p>
                  <p>
                    <quote xml:lang="syr"/>
                  </p>
                </item>
                <item>
                  <locus from="2a" to=""/>
                  <p>A marginal note on fol. 2 a shows that a life of "John the bishop" was once
                    bound with this manuscript</p>
                  <p>
                    <quote xml:lang="syr">ܬܫܥ̈ܝܬܐ ܕܓܪܝܓܪܝܘܣ ܐܦܝܣܩܦܐ܀ ܘܕܡܪܝ ܝܘܚܢܢ ܐܦܝ̣ܣܩܦܐ܀</quote>
                  </p>
                </item>
              </list>
            </additions>
            <bindingDesc>
              <p>Content pending</p>
            </bindingDesc>
            <sealDesc>
              <p>Content pending</p>
            </sealDesc>
            <accMat/>
          </physDesc>
          <history>
            <origin>
              <origDate notBefore="" notAfter="" from="0500" to="0600" when="">VIth
                Century</origDate>
              <origPlace ref="" xml:lang=""></origPlace>
            </origin>
            <provenance/>
            <acquisition/>
          </history>
          <additional/>
        </msDesc>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <p>Content pending</p>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc/>
    <revisionDesc status="draft">
      <change when="2021-05-17" who="http://syriaca.org/documentation/editors.xml#rbrasoveanu"
        >Initial TEI encoding.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <formula>Content pending</formula>
  </facsimile>
  <text>
    <body>
      <bibl>Content pending</bibl>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
