<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <msDesc>
        <msIdentifier>DCCCCLXXXIX</msIdentifier>
        <note>Twelve vellum leaves, about 10 7/8 in. by 7 1/4, the first three of which are much soiled
            and torn. They formed parts of three quires, numbered $ܝܛ , ܟ, and $ܟܐ , but there are
            considerable lacunae after foll. 1 and 2. Each page is divided into two columns, of from
            27 to 30 lines. The writing is neat and regular, and seems to be of the ix<sup>th</sup>
            ccnt. They con­tain—</note>
        <msItem><title xml:lang="en">Works of Severus Sabocht, bishop of Kinnesrin (see Assemani, Bibl. Or., t. ii., p.
            335); viz— </title><msItem><idno>1.</idno>
                <title xml:lang="en">Fragments of a commentary on the % of Aristotle.</title>
                <locus>Foll. 1 and 2.</locus>
                <note>This may, however, be the work of some other author.</note></msItem>
            <msItem><idno>2.</idno>
                <title xml:lang="en">A treatise on the Syllogisms in the Analytica (Priora) of
                    Aristotle.</title>
                <locus>Fol 3 a.</locus>
                <note>Imperfect at the beginning; see Add. 14,660, no. 2.</note>
                <finalRubric xml:lang="syr"><locus>fol. 5 b:</locus>ܫܠ̣ܡ ܡܐܡܪܐ ܕܒܙܥܘܪܝܬܐ ܕܡܛܠ
                    ܣܘܠܘܓܝܣܡܘܣ ܕܒܐܢܐܘܠܘܛܝܩܐ ܕܐܪܝܣܛܛܠܝܣ ܕܥܒܝܕ ܠܚܣܝܐ ܐܒܘܣ ܡܪܝ ܣܐܘܪܐ ܐܦܝܣܩܘܦܐ ܕܩܢ̣ܫܪܝܢ
                </finalRubric></msItem>
            <msItem><idno>3.</idno>
                <title xml:lang="en">A letter to Jonas, the periodeutes, ex­planatory of some points
                    in the Ars Rhetorica of Aristotle.</title>
                <locus>Fol. 5 b.</locus><rubric xml:lang="syr"> ܬܘܒ ܐܝܓܪܬܐ ܕܚܣܝܐ ܣܐܘܪܐ ܣܒܘܟܬ ܐܦܝܣܩܦܐ
                    ܕܩܢ̇ܫܪܝܢ: ܠܘܬ ܣܥܘܪܐ ܝܘܢܢ ܪܚ̇ܡܗ ܡܛܠ ܦܘܫܩܐ ܡܕܡ ܡܕܡ ܡܢ ܐܘܡܢܘܬܐ ܡܠܝܠܬܐ ܕܐܪܝܣܛܛܠܝܣ
                    ܦܝܠܣܦܐ</rubric><incipit xml:lang="syr">ܠܪܚ̇ܡ ܐܠܗܐ ܘܕܚܠ ܠܐܠܗܐ̇. ܐܚܘܢ ܪܘܚܢܐ ܘܚܒܝܒܐ
                    ܩܫܝܫܐ ܘܣܥܘܪܐ ܝܘܢܢ܆ ܣܐܘܪܐ ܒܨܝܪܐ ܒܡܪܝܐ ܚ̣ܕܝ.܀ ܩܒܠܬ ܐܦ ܗܫܐ ܠܐܝܓܪܬܐ ܕܐܚܘܬܟ ܪܘܚܢܝܬܐ.
                    ܐܦܢ ܘܠܡܚܣܢ ܘܡܫܘܚܪܐܝܬ: ܒܬܪ ܫܢܬܐ ܓܝܪ ܚܕܐ ܠܥܢܝܢܐ ܗ̇ܘ ܕܥ̇ܒܕܬ̇ ܠܘܬ ܚܘܒܟ ܐܬ̣ܐ ܠܘܬܝ.
                    ܘܪܒܬܝ ܚܕܝܬ. ܕܐܣܬܒܪܬ ܐܝܟ ܥܝܕܐ̇. ܥܠ ܫܦܝܪܘܬ ܚܘܠܡܢܐ ܕܕܚܠܬ ܐܠܗܐ ܕܝܠܟ. ܐܟܚܕܐ ܕܝܢ
                    ܘܕܫܦܪܬ ܠܣܟܘܠܬܢܘܬܐ ܕܐܚ̇ܘܬܟ. ܡܥܗܕܢܘܬܐ ܗ̇ܝ ܕܗܘ̣ܬ ܡܢܝ܇ ܡܛܠ ܦܘܫ̈ܟܐ ܗ̇ܢܘܢ ܕܗܘ̣ܘ ܠܗ
                    ܒܙܒܢ܇ ܡܛܠ ܩܢܘ̈ܢܐ ܡܕܡ ܡܕܡ̇. ܕܐܒܗ̈ܬܐ ܩ̈ܕܝܫܐ܀ ܏ܘܫ.</incipit></msItem>
            <msItem><idno>4.</idno>
                <title xml:lang="en">A letter to the priest #Aitilaha on certain terms in the
                    treatise %</title>
                <locus>Fol. 11 a.</locus>
                <rubric xml:lang="syr">ܐܓܪܬܐ ܕܚܣܝܐ ܣܐܘܪܐ ܣܒܘܟܬ. ܡܛܠ ܒ̈ܢܬ ܩ̈ܠܐ ܡ̣ܕܡ ܕܒܟܬܒܐ
                    ܕܦܪܝܪܡܢܝܐܣ. ܠܘܬ ܩܫܝܫܐ ܐܝܬܝܠܗܐ</rubric>
                <note>Imperfect at the end. See Add. 14,660, no. 3.</note></msItem>
        </msItem>
        <note>These leaves arc decorated with interlaced ornaments and figures of birds; e.g. foll. 4 b, 5 b, and 9 a.</note>
        <msIdentifier>Add. 17,156, foll. 1—12</msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
</root>
